<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science | Amy Gill</title>
    <link>/tags/data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Science</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Data Science</title>
      <link>/tags/data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Capstone: Breast Cancer Prediction</title>
      <link>/project/brca-ds-capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/brca-ds-capstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was my capstone project for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/professional-certificate/harvardx-data-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HarvardX Data Science Professional Certificate&lt;/a&gt;. It demonstrates competency in R programming, statstical modeling and basic machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this study was to train a machine learning classifier to predict whether a breast tumor is malignant (cancer) or benign (not cancer) based on cell nucleus features extracted from digitized images of breast biopsy slides. It makes use of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Breast+Cancer+Wisconsin+(Diagnostic)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Breast Cancer Wisconsin Diagnostic Data Set&lt;/a&gt;, a classic machine learning benchmarking dataset. Results and implications are analyzed from the perspective of a cancer biologist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HarvardX Data Science Series Updates</title>
      <link>/project/dslabs-dsbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/dslabs-dsbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I began programming as a student in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/professional-certificate/harvardx-data-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HarvardX Data Science Professional Program&lt;/a&gt;, a massive open online course series from Rafael Irizarry on edX.
To become more comfortable with coding and project workflows, I contributed dozens of edits to the course textbook, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rafalab.github.io/dsbook/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to Data Science&lt;/a&gt;, via its open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rafalab/dsbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. I initially acted as a volunteer, systematically revewing the textbook and acting as a community teaching assistant, but my diligence earned me a full-time position improving the course series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the new lead content developer for the program, my first major project was to write additional assessments for the courses in order to add value to the certificate. I formatted these problem sets as case studies and included relevant data in the course series R package, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/dslabs/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dslabs&lt;/strong&gt;, available on CRAN&lt;/a&gt;. I added 7 new datasets to &lt;strong&gt;dslabs&lt;/strong&gt; with documentation and scripts. I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplystatistics.org/2019/07/19/more-datasets-for-teaching-data-science-the-expanded-dslabs-package/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guest post on Simply Statistics&lt;/a&gt; describing the new datasets and demonstrating some potential uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new problem sets launched in the July 2019 versions of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/professional-certificate/harvardx-data-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HarvardX Data Science Professional Certificate&lt;/a&gt; courses, which currently have over 75,000 unique enrolled learners. In that course release, I also added supplemental notes and links to the accompanying textbook on every content page. I currently supervise a team of TAs answering student queries on the course discussion boards and maintain existing materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current projects involve revising the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/xseries/genomics-data-analysis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HarvardX Genomics Data Analysis XSeries&lt;/a&gt; for release in March 2020 and co-authoring the official solution manual for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rafalab.github.io/dsbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Introduction to Data Science textbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
